dnl.blm@gmail.com linkedin.com

UX/UI Designer with experience in different market segments. I've designed creative interfaces and interactions using design best practices and balancing business and user needs. I also have front-end skills that allow me to better design and communicate with developers. I'm a dedicated, problem-solving, and collaborative person who loves to exchange experiences and to improve products and processes.

Professional Experience

UI and Interaction Designer

Fiocruz (Freelancer) | 2021-2022

Online education

- Organized the design system, resulting in a better alignment of the course production team.
- Improved navigation and interactions, facilitating users' access to educational content.
- Built interfaces using HTML, CSS, and JS, making them accessible and adapted to the client's needs.

UX/UI Design

Benie | 2020-2021

Health Tech startup

- Redesigned the app and website, according to the new branding, to meet business needs.
- Organized the style guide of the UI elements, facilitating communication with developers.
- Designed features based on business needs and users' behavior while using the app, improving the
 User Experience and growing sales.

UI and Interaction Designer

Beep Saúde | 2018-2020

Health Tech startup

- Designed landing pages for internal and marketing projects, strengthening brand's presence and bringing new customers.
- Implemented metrics on the team, measuring performance and workload.
- Created new employee onboarding products, increasing their engagement with the company.

UX/UI Design

Freelancer | 2015-2018

 Developed desktop and mobile interfaces for different startups and companies. I developed wireframes, navigation flows, high-fidelity prototypes, and front ends that improved their business operations, communication, and management.

Founder, Visual and Game Designer

Duckbill | 2012-2015

Newsgame startup

- Created game design documents, with rules, characters, gameplay, and all information needed to guide
 the development team.
- Designed the games visual identities and assets.
- Prototyped test and demonstration versions of the games in low- and high-fidelity.

Graphic and Industrial Designer

Clan Design | 2007 - 2013

Exhibitions, signaling and urban furniture

- Introduced 3D modeling, creating small-scale and furniture models for better project preview.
- Designed interactive exhibition presentations, providing an immersive experience to potential sponsors.

Skills

USER EXPERIENCE

Design System, Wireframe, User Flows, Layout, Responsive Design, Prototype (high- and lowfidelity), Specifications, Usability Testing.

FRONT-FND

HTML, CSS, JavaScript
Bootstrap, and libraries to
customize animations and style.

Tools

Adobe Creative Cloud (Illustrator, Photoshop, XD, InDesign) Figma, Axure, VSCode, GitHub, Trello.

Education

Specialization in Ergodesign: Usability and Information Architecture PUC-Rio I 2015-2016

Bachelor of Industrial Design UniverCidade I 2001-2007

Game Development. Azimut I 2009-2011

Interesting areas

User Interface Design
Interaction Design
User Experience Design
Front-end development

Technology

Innovation

Internet of Things (IoT)

Languages

Portuguese	Native speake
English	Intermediate
Spanish	Intermediate
Hebrew	Intermediate